

Brendan M. Quinn brendanquinn89@gmail.com (+49) 015773365297 LinkedIn – Twitter

Personal Profile American master degree graduate with three years product and management experience who, as Product Owner and Manager, can facilitate the process from product vision to product release, while heavily integrating and improving user experience. Also has the ability to work in high level stress environments while exhibiting strong communication, social, and project management skills.

Areas of Expertise **Product and Project Management**: leading small/large teams, in an Agile environment, through a product roadmap with strict time restrictions.

Cross-communication/bridging between Design and Engineering to develop and launch both Web and Mobile apps.

Product Marketing: Formulating and executing online and offline marketing campaigns and building product awareness.

User Experience: Conducting and integrating UX principles/tasks to increase overall engagement and conversion rates. These include KPIs, metrics, user personas, wireframing, navigation models, extensive potential/existing user interviews, surveys, questionnaires, A/B Testing

Business Development and Market Research: Identifying and making strategic partnerships in Europe, US, and South America

archify and blippex
Berlin, Germany, Internet Startup
2012- 2013

Work
Experience



Product Management: Worked with engineering and UX/UI teams to develop and execute requirements for Web and Android products. Managed the SCRUM Agile development Heavy focus on UX pre/post launch with establishing KPIs, metrics, testing, interviews, and questionnaires.

Other responsibilities include Product Owner, SCRUM master, Copywriting, User Support

Product Marketing: Formulated and executed multiple paid online (AdWords, Facebook Ads) and offline (events, sponsorship) marketing campaigns in Berlin. Evangelized and built product awareness across social media channels and PR. Created promotional videos and maintained company blog by posting relevant content.. Selected press coverage including <u>LifeHacker</u>, <u>BBC</u>, <u>GigaOM</u>.

Working with a Berlin video production company on releasing the archify promotional video: http://vimeo.com/52487421

Musicoev, Founder

Madrid, Spain 2011-2012



Worked on a self-project of creating a social network for musicians in Madrid and other surrounding cities in Spain. Worked with web developers, programmers, and business developers and created a functional beta prototype that was tested with an alpha group in the city.

Analyst at Accenture Global Management Consulting

accenture

Madrid, Spain 2011-2012 Worked on a project with Banco Santander's Sovereign Bank acquisition in the United States and other projects in South America and Germany. Learned basic COBOL programming and worked with consulting and management teams within these projects analyzing data, researching market opportunities, competitor analysis, and also maintained client relationships.

Internship at Accenture Global Management Consulting



Madrid, Spain 2010

Worked on various projects with Banco Santander as an Accenture representative. Consulting with Santander's Isban software division to transfer and coordinate on various projects.

Business Research Assistant Muhlenberg College

Allentown, PA, USA Spring Employment, 2009-2011



Worked with university business and economics professors on a national publication concerning the vitality of the arts and music in the United States. Gathered large amount of data and conducted several interviews.

Education

Masters in International Business

Universidad de Alcalá Madrid, Spain 2011-2012



Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration and International Relations

Muhlenberg College Allentown, PA, USA 2007-2011



Study Abroad Business Program

University of Maastricht

Maastricht, Netherlands, Fall 2009-Spring 2010



Tools/Skills

- Certified Scrum Product Owner
- Experience as a Product Owner and Scrum Master in SCRUM/Lean Agile Development
- JIRA, Confluence, and Trello
- Salesforce's Desk CRM
- Google Analytics for Web and Mobile
- A/B Testing (In House, Optimizely)
- CrazyEgg heat mapping
- Mailchimp email service provider
- Kissmetrics/Mixpanel
- Rapid Prototyping with Balsamiq Mockups
- Telestream ScreenFlow UX Testing
- Google Ad-Words
- SEO Marketing
- Facebook Ads
- Creating promotional product videos

Technical

Experience/

Elastic Search

•Web applications on Chrome Firefox Safari and

ills •Web

- •Web applications on Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and Opera
- Mobile browser applications including Dolphin, Android native, and Firefox Mobile

•Leading web projects built in Python, PHP, Ruby, HTML, Java, Angular JS, JavaScript, and

- Android and iOS platforms
- Excel and MySQL
- •Intermediate HTML5, CSS3, and COBOL programming

Language Native English and fluent Spanish
 Skills
 Interests Hiking, Walking, Playing/Writing Music, Computer/Mobile games, Technology, Traveling
 Facts Musician, Guitarist, Violinist, Songwriter. Recorded 3 EPs and one full length album in past 2 years.
 Completed the Camino De Santiago hike/pilgrimage in Northern Spain.
 I have a twin sister.